# **Alaa Eldin Mohamed Alageed Mohamed**

Mobile Number: +966555618060

Date of Birth: 12/09/1987
Marital status: Married
wadal3geed@hotmail.com
Address: Riyadh, Sudai Arabia











#### **Personal Profiles**

An accomplished 10 years in ICT professional with hands on experience of multiple vendors and products. Possess strong technical knowledge, planning and design, hardware installation, software commissioning, integration, operations and maintenance skills and I Have experience on Firewall and HP SAN Storage, AVAYA, Cisco iP phone, ERP System

#### Certification:

- Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITILv4)
- MCSA: Windows Server 2016
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA R/S)
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA voice)
- Network Security Associate (Fortinet)

#### **Technical Expertise:**

**System:** Windows Server 2003,2008,2012,2016,

**Servers:** HP DL380p Gen8, KVM.

**Network:** Cisco Catalyst 3750, 2960, 4503-E, 4900M. Routers 2800, 3725, 7200,

**Firewall:** FortiGate,

**Monitoring:** Dameweare, PRTG, NetFlow. SEIM, And Splunk

**Network tools**: Wireshark

Virtualization: VMware - Hyper V

### **Professional Experience:**

Company Saudi Telecom Company (STC), Saudi Arabia, Riyadh

Role **Technical Specialist Engineer** 

Dates Nov 2015 – Present Description Technical Specialist

# Sic

## Responsibilities

- Provided services as a Technical Specialist in Enterprise Technology Centre, assisting on resolving enterprise
  customers faults and issues, by troubleshooting the issues using STC systems and getting in touch with Network
  NMCs (TNOC, MNOC, DNOC, ANOC, etc.) & Field operations NOCs (DATA, FIXED & FTTx) to resolve the issue in the
  minimum possible time. In addition, to provide the needed support to sales team members.
- responsible of Data Circuits Lyer2 & Lyer3 Tier2 support by performing a live troubleshoot with STC enterprise
  customers at all circuit levels by checking circuit design, configuration, access and troubleshoot from MPLS last PE
  (Provider Edge) for all vendors Cisco, Huawei and Juniper to verify MAC,VLAN, VRF, Bgp status, Bandwidth, link
  traffic ..etc. for IP-VPN, PLL, DIA, SIP and other services.
- Conducted troubleshooting and analysis of customers issues and monitored circuits, tracked customers complains for all services, enhancing the processes and preparing technical reports.
- Monitoring EBU VIP customers' circuits through a live dashboard to detect, analyze and escalate issues in time.
   Data circuits & Landline faults analysis.
- RCA reports preparation for customers and sales.
- STC high management notification regarding planned MDTs & Major Outage in coordination with NNCC team.
- Participating in EBU workshops for new services launching.
- Assisting in section's performance reports preparation. (Weekly, Monthly, Quarterly & Annually reports).
- Assisting in preparations of section's SLA or OLA with others EBU sections.

Company Role Dates

Description

Ministry of Interior Sudan
IT administrator and Network Support Engineer
Jun 2011 – Sep 2015

**IT administrator and Network Support Engineer** 



# Responsibilities

- Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, exchange server 2013 deployment for Windows 2012 R2.
- SAN storage HP ,Stratage of the Backup HP out loader with help of Symantecsoftware
- Analyze cyber threat data and correlate with existing understanding of our company environments. Perform post mortem analysis on logs, traffic flows, and other activities to identify malicious activity.
- Coordinate with SOC Analyst team to ensure a continual flow of updated threat content to the SIEM systems and Security Systems.
- Lead 'hunt exercises' using threat intelligence, analysis of anomalous log data and results of brainstorming sessions to detect and eradicate threat actors within the Hikma environment. Provide expert analytic investigative support of complex security incidents.
- Suggest modifications to internal defenses and continuously improve processes for more effective and efficient security operations.
- Help develop dashboards and reports to identify potential threats, suspicious/anomalous activity, IOCs and malware, etc.
- Participate in knowledge sharing with other Analysts and writing technical articles for internal knowledge bases.
- Attend meetings within SOC to review cyber threats, required actions and suggest improvements.
- Reviewing weekly, monthly and on demand threat intelligence reports.
- Trouble-Ticket Report Updating , closure & Internal and External Coordination
- Setup security policies for users. and computer security (e.g. firewalls and intrusion detection systems). Deploying VMs, Virtual machine creation, cloning, and configuration.
- Working on ERP SAGEX3 as supporting.
- Avaya IP Phone Configuration and installation and troubleshoot.
- Hyper-v2 on windows server 2012 R2
- Working Fort iGATE firewall.
- Lead Teams of Technicians to perform implementation.

#### **Projects Included**

- 1.ERP system
- 2. Hyper-v Clustring.
- 3.TMG 2010 installing and configuration .
- 4. Avaya IP Phone configuration and installation on PBX 5000 AVAYA.
- 5.TT system Help Desk system.
- 6. (Data Center).

Company Role system Dates Description

IATL International (Sudan, Khartoum)

**Administrator** 

Agu 2009 – May 2011 System Administrator



#### Responsibilities

- Active Directory, DNS, DHCP deployment for Windows 2012 R2, windows server 2008 R2.
- Group Policy, SCCM and WSUS. Under the Domain.
- File Server management.
- Lead a shift of engineers to perform routine T-shoot tasks of reporting, alarms monitoring and escalation.
- Trouble-Ticket Report Updating , closure & Internal and External Coordination
- Provide level 2/3 line support for the issues escalated by monitoring team and coordinate with R&D to follow-up pending issues.
- Setup security policies for users. And computer security (e.g. firewalls and intrusion detection systems). Deploying VMs, Virtual machine creation, cloning, and configuration.
- Good sense in Data backup, restoration and DR planning.
- Network Project Follow-up and meeting with Consultant/Customer.
- Lead Teams of Technicians to perform implementation.
- Implement Network Infrastructures (Voice/Data), Data Center
- Implement Layer 2 Technologies STP, RSTP, MSTP, VTP, VLANs, Trunk, Ether Channel.
- Design and implement network connectivity solutions based on business requirements.
- Setup security policies for users. A sys admin must have a strong grasp of computer security (e.g. firewalls and intrusion detection systems).
- Configure and monitor routing protocol operation RIP V2, OSPF, EIGRP.
- Implementing and managing Cisco routers with IP, NAT & ACL.
- Configuring and implementing Remote Access Solution: IPSec VPN, EasyVPN, SSL VPN.
- Monitor system performance

#### **Training Courses**

- CCNA (R/S)
- (CCNA VOICE)
- ITILv4
- Windows Server 2016
- Root Cause Analysis Skills (STC), Dubai
- Customer Relationship Management CRM
- Crisis Management It
- IT Of Business
- Network Management

#### **EDUCATION**

**2005-2009 BSc computer Engineering,** Future University, Khartoum-**Sudan.** 

#### **Attributes:**

- Passion
- Respect
- Integrity
- Discipline
- Customer oriented
- Strong interpersonal skills

#### Skill:

- Troubleshooting under Microsoft server and cisco routing
- Multi-task
- Demonstrable experience of analyzing and interpreting system, security and application logs in order to diagnose faults and spot abnormal behavior.
- Ability to prepare and present research findings.
- Proven ability to find, evaluate and succinctly summarize and analyze information.
- Knowledge of Cyber Threat Intelligence, Software vulnerabilities & exploitation and Data Analysis
- Able to help and learning. Within a team or without.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic: Native, English: Fluent